

Personal details



Enrique Alberto Niebles Saco



esaconn@gmail.com



+49 177 5030382



Am Helmholtzring 2 e 98693 Ilmenau, Germany



Colombian



linkedin.com/in/esaconn

Languages

Spanish	••••
English	••••
German	••••

Skills

Teamwork and team management

Leadership skills

Java, Python und SQL

Knowledge in web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React)

Data Analytics, Data Visualization

Hobbies

- Read manga and comics
- Walking in nature
- Bowling

Enrique Alberto Niebles Saco

Profile

I am an outstanding electrical engineering student who is pursuing a double degree in computer science and systems engineering. My high academic and scientific level and my initiative distinguish me. Thanks to my training, I have leadership skills and knowledge in public management. In addition, I speak several languages, which enriches my professional experience. My technical skills include various programming languages that I use for software development and solving technical challenges. My professional profile focuses on software architecture, signal analysis, artificial intelligence, and data science.

Employment

Academic tutor for Discrete Structures subject

Jan 2021 - Jul 2022

Resource Center for Student Success (CREE), Universidad del Norte. Barranquilla,

- Academic supervision of students.
- Combinatorial analysis.
- Algorithms of graph theory.
- Recurrence relations.
- Recursive function design.
- Ordinary and Exponential Generating Functions.
- Using Python, Matlab and Visual Basic to solve problems.

Academic tutor for Communication systems

Iul 2021 - Nov 2021

Resource Center for Student Success (CREE), Universidad del Norte. Barranquilla, Colombia

- Academic supervision of students.
- Use of Python and Matlab for analysis of stochastic processes.
- Understanding of AM and FM modulations.
- Frequency and time analysis of a signal.
- Passband and digital communications.

Vice-chair of the Vehicular Technology Society

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

IEEE Student branch Universidad del Norte, Barranquilla, Colombia

- Manage social networks and communication channels of the chapter or affinity
- Co-lead the National Events of the Branch, taken over by the IEEE Branch Uninorte.
- Working collaboratively with a work team on a topic and under the supervision of a responsible
- First-hand interaction with members and participants of the activities.
- Receiving the various trainings offered by the Branch Manager to improve

Courses

German as a foreign language B2.2 (2 months) Carl Duisberg Center. Cologne, Germany.	Sep 2022
Seeds for the future training program Huawei Technologies.	Sep 2021

Industry 4.0 business opportunities Sep 2021 Universidad EAN.

Leadership and emotional education Jan 2021 Fundación Liderazgo Chile FLICH.

Artificial Intelligence Aug 2020 MINTIC and Platzi course with 200 theoretical and practical hours.

References

Ing. Alfonso M. Mancilla Herrera, M.Sc. Ph.D.

Universidad del Norte, Barranquilla, Colombia

+57 3003927877. amancill@uninorte.edu.co

Ing. M.Sc. Enrique E. Niebles Nuñez, Ph.D.

Universidad Autónoma del Caribe, Barranquilla, Colombia

+57 3135460052, enieblesn@gmail.com

Education

Computer Science Technische Universität Ilmenau, Ilmenau, Germany	Oct 2022 - Present
Computer Science	Iul 2019 - Present

Universidad del Norte, Barranquilla, Colombia

Electronics engineer Jan 2018 - Nov 2022

Universidad del Norte, Barranquilla, Colombia

Data Scientist Mar 2022 - Jul 2022 Correlation One

Programming skills training program Mar 2021 - Dec 2021 Universidad de Antioquia, Medellín, Colombia

Achievements

- Scholarship for education and training in Germany KOSPIE 22/23. German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD), Germany.
- Graduated with honors, 2022. data science 4 all. Correlation One.
- Electrical engineering dean's list, 2022-I. Universidad del Norte, Colombia.
- Huawei Technologies Seeds for the Future Program 3rd place, 2021. Huawei Technologies.
- Seeds for the Future Program scholarship recipient, 2021. Huawei Technologies.
- Electrical Engineering 2020-II dean's list. Universidad del Norte, Colombia.
- Sakura Science Exchange Program scholarship recipient, 2017. Japan Science and Technology Agency.
- Ser Pilo Paga 4 Scholarship, 2017. ICETEX, Colombia.
- Academic Excellence Award, 2017. IDDI Nueva Granada, Colombia.